JOSEF ADAMČÍK

ANDROID DEVELOPER, SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Profile

I perceive myself as a self-reliant problem solver, a humble craftsman and a permanent learner. I value gradual improvement over big restarts/rewrites. I believe that clean code, automated testing, code reviews, CI/CD and other good practices are crucial parts of high-quality software development, but the most important thing is to deliver value.

Skills

Android development

I am a skilled Android developer with deep knowledge of Java and Android platform. I keep eye on new trends and technologies (e.g. Kotlin, Flutter, React Native).

Back-end development

I have experience in API design and back-end development in PHP (Symfony) and Java (Spring, Hibernate, JSF). Due to my focus on Android development, some of my skills in this area might require a slight refresh.

Web front-end development

Although my skills in this area are a bit outdated, I had had a strong knowledge of JavaScript and related technologies in the times before React changed everything.

Experience

Freelance

Android developer

I help companies with their software projects.

2018-current

Smarcoms

Software developer

2006-2018

I worked for Smarcoms for almost 12 years. I started as a student and continued my career in the company after I had finished my degree. The company changed a lot during all those years and I met a lot of developers, learned a lot of technologies and participated in many interesting projects.

I started as a website developer (PHP, Symfony) but I soon moved to other projects.

I was part of a team which developed a mid-scale Java web application - booking system for sports centres called Bizzy. My role was to do a full-stack development. I worked with technologies like Java, Spring, Hibernate, JSF, Richfaces, PostgreSQL, Tomcat.

Next big project was a mobile application Shopin - Czech mall/retail guide. The application consisted of a backend with API, web app for administering, several services for data gathering, and two mobile apps for Android and iOs. Mobile applications started as hybrid HTML5 apps supported by Cordova (formerly PhoneGap) and later evolved to into native applications. I participated as a lead backend developer and hybrid mobile app developer, later as a native Android developer. Technologies were: PHP, Symfony, Java, JavaScript, Python, MySQL and others.

There were many other projects I worked on. I developed several Android applications for various clients, built backends for those applications (or helped to build them). I helped to support legacy projects of our clients and solved various problems our clients had trouble with. I grew into a "go to" person for most of my colleagues.

Technical

Android	Kotlin	Java	
JavaScript	PHP	Symfony	
SQL	HTML	CSS	
Spring	Hibernate	JSF	
PostgreSQL	MySQL	Python	
Django	Drupal	Git	
SVN	Linux	Testing	
CI	Cordova	JUnit	
Espresso	TDD		

Languages Czech

English

proficient

German

beginner (I am in the learning process and currently unable to offer cooperation in the German language)

Education

Software Engineering in Economics, master degree

CVUT FJFI 2006-2010

Czech Technical University in Prague, Faculty of Nuclear Sciences and Physical Engineering

Software Engineering in Economics, bachelor degree

CVUT FJFI 2003-2006

Czech Technical University in Prague, Faculty of Nuclear Sciences and Physical Engineering

electronics, computer technology

SPŠ strojní a dopravní v Děčíně 1999-2003

Links

Website (info, resume, blog)

josef-adamcik.cz

Github

github.com/josefadamcik

Stackoverflow

stackoverflow.com/users/135837/josef-adamcik

Showcase project (Android + Kotlin)

github.com/josefadamcik/TrackOnTrakt

Josef Adamčík — josef.adamcik@gmail.com —